Have you ever heard of a tri? No, not the verb try. I'm talking about the data structure called a tri,
spelled T-R-I-E. Imagine you're organizing a massive library but instead of books you're
dealing with words. A tri is like a tree of arrays that allows you to store and retrieve
these words at lightning-fast speeds. Picture each letter of the alphabet having its own shelf.
To store a word, you simply place it on the shelf corresponding to its first letter.
Then each subsequent letter gets its own subshelf branching off from the previous one.
The magic happens when you're looking for a specific word. No matter how many words are
in the library, you can find any word in the same amount of time just by following the path
created by its letters. So the next time you're typing on your phone and the keyboard seems to
magically predict the word you want, remember the humble tree? The unsung hero of lightning-fast
word retrieval.